chargepoint.com 2018-12-28

# ChargePoint Website Privacy Policy | ChargePoint

### Effective Date: May 15, 2018

ChargePoint® has created this privacy policy to demonstrate its commitment to the privacy of its customers and users. This privacy policy applies to this website, including the portion of the website accessed by ChargePoint customers and users (collectively, the "Web Site"), and the service offered by ChargePoint, including through use of the ChargePoint Smart Cards (the "Service"). By using this Web Site and the Service or by transmitting information to us by email or other electronic means, you agree to this privacy policy.

### 1\. Changes to Privacy Policy

We may change and update this privacy policy from time to time, so you should check back to this page for the updated policy. For any significant changes affecting your personally identifiable information, we will post a more prominent notice to the Web Site of the change. If you disagree with any change, you must stop using the Service.

Otherwise, we will consider your continued use to be acceptance of the change.

### 2\. Information Collection and Usage

ChargePoint collects different kinds of information through the Web Site and the Service, and uses this information in different ways.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information. When you visit the Web Site we collect certain demographic information (such as your IP address, type of Internet browser and operating system you use, pages viewed, the URL that you visited before you came to our Web Site, and the URL to which you next go) in order to understand how users navigate through the Web Site and to improve your experience using the Web Site.

Personally Identifiable Information. If you sign up for the Service or use the Service or send email or other communication to ChargePoint, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our Web Site and Service. In registering for the Service, we need to get some information from you (like name, title, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card or other means of payment, etc.). When using the Service, you may be asked for additional information to help identify you. All of this information used to specifically identify you is called "User Information" in this privacy policy. We only collect User Information that you provide to us or have given us permission to collect.

When you use our Service, we collect certain demographic information (such as your ChargePoint charging station location and charging duration) in order to understand usage patterns and to improve your experience using our Service. 

We use the User Information in order to process the application, to provide the Service to the customer and users and to otherwise communicate with you as a customer or user regarding the Service. Please keep in mind that we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to your use of the Service, such as service announcements, notices about new features or information on the Service, administrative messages and communications regarding your account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them. 

We also may use the User Information to provide advertisements from ChargePoint or its partners to you, but you will have the opportunity to opt-out of these communications.

From time to time, you may receive offers through ChargePoint from other businesses. These offers may require you to provide information to them if you choose to accept their offers. You should remember that these offers are made by the businesses themselves and not by ChargePoint. You should always be sure to read the terms of service and privacy policies of these businesses before providing any information to them so that you can understand their intended uses for your information. ChargePoint may receive information from these regarding your response to their offers so that ChargePoint may better tailor your user experience. 

From time to time, we may also collect information via online surveys or polls. Participation in these surveys or polls is entirely voluntary and you may easily decline to participate. 

Aggregated Information. ChargePoint may also analyze and compile information on patterns of usage of the Service. This information is collected in aggregate form, without identifying any user individually. We may use this information to improve the Service and provide this information to third parties for marketing purposes.

Cookies. Please refer to our “Cookies and other similar technologies” policy for information on how we use cookies and similar technologies. Like most websites, we use cookies and similar technologies to provide users an efficient experience in using the Website as well as certain web analytics tools for the purpose of analysing your use of the Website and the Service, compiling reports on the Website and the Service activity for ChargePoint and providing ChargePoint other services relating to activity on the Website and the Service. So we do recommend that you read and understand that policy as well.

For more detailed information about the use of cookies on our Website please see here <https://www.chargepoint.com/cookie-policy/>.

Children’s Privacy. The Web Site and the Service are intended for adult users, and ChargePoint does not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under 13 years of age.

### 3\. Information Sharing

We generally do not share with any third party User Information in a way that would personally identify you. However, we may do so in the following circumstances:

  * (a) as part of a merger, acquisition or any form of sale of some or all of ChargePoint assets or business,
  * (b) to our service providers and other contractors for the purposes of providing Service to us (such contractors are prohibited from using User Information for any other purpose),
  * (c) for bill collection;
  * (d) to resolve customer disputes or inquiries;
  * (e) to a Program Partner (as defined herein) (but only if you are participating in an offer or program offered by ChargePoint in conjunction with one of its partners (each, a "Program Partner")), in order for ChargePoint and the Program Partner to provide the Service, confirm that you are eligible to participate in such offer or program (e.g., by sharing and verifying the VIN of your vehicle), and for the Program Partner to understand your usage patterns and to improve its offer or program with ChargePoint or other offers, programs or services offered by the Program Partner;
  * (f) in the unlikely event of insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which your personal information would be transferred as one of ChargePoint’s business assets; and
  * (g) where we are legally obligated to disclose information to the government or third parties for the purposes of national security, law enforcement or other issues of public importance.

We may aggregate information and data about you and your use of the Web Site and Service and provide such aggregated information and data to advertisers and for marketing or promotional purposes. In these circumstances, we do not disclose information that could be used to personally identify you.

ChargePoint is potentially liable for onward transfers to third parties of personal data of citizens and residents of the European Union or Switzerland received pursuant to Privacy Shield.

Access by ChargePoint, its distributors, ChargePoint charging station owners, or authorized third parties, or their respective employees and consultants to any personal information you provide is limited to only information necessary to provide the business service offered and to allow employees or consultants to perform their duties.

### 4\. Security Measures

To help protect the privacy of the data you transmit through the Web Site or Service, ChargePoint uses industry-standard; secure server software that encrypts the information you input before it is sent to us. In addition, ChargePoint uses standard industry practice to protect User Information against unauthorized access. However, you should keep in mind that the Web Site and Service are run on software, hardware and networks, any component of which may from time to time require maintenance or experience problems or breaches of security beyond our control and for which we are not responsible.

### 5\. Links to Third-Party Websites

This Web Site may contain links to third party sites. Access to any other Internet site linked to this Web Site is at the user’s own risk and ChargePoint is not responsible for the accuracy or reliability of any information, data, opinions, advice or statements made on these sites. ChargePoint provides these links merely as a convenience and the inclusion of such links does not imply an endorsement.

### 6\. Accessing Your User Information

We will try to update your User Information as we become aware of changes. However, we will be able to serve you best if you update your User Information or notify us of any may submit a written request for changes to (or errors in) your User Information by contacting ChargePoint Customer Service at the addressed set forth below in Section 10. You can update your User Information through the Web Site or if you are unable to access that information for any reason, you listed below. In order for us to serve you best, please provide your name, phone number, mailing address, and e-mail address when contacting us.

### 7\. Consent to Processing

ChargePoint is a global company which operates its Website and Service through servers located in a number of countries. If you select a country in Europe as your country of residence, your personal data is hosted on servers within the European Union.

We will need to access or view your personal data, (including your name, full address, email address, telephone number, security question and information about your vehicle including your license number and the make, model, color of your vehicle), via a secure network from the United States in order for ChargePoint to provide you with our support services or to troubleshoot any issues to improve our support services. In order to develop and improve our products and services for users, and to provide statistical information to third parties including, but not limited to, government bodies, utilities and auto manufacturers. ChargePoint will transfer certain data back to the United States (including pseudonymized information coupled with session data such as length of charge, location of charge, amount of energy received and fee). We may also need to access pseudonymized information via a secure network from the United States for financial accounting purposes. By registering for an account and submitting your personal data **you consent to the transfer, processing and/or storing of your personal data on servers located in the United States** , and acknowledge that the level of data protection in the United States is not necessarily equivalent to the level of data protection within the European Union and the European Economic Area. We will take necessary steps to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy.

### 8\. Governing Law

The Web Site is controlled and operated by ChargePoint. By choosing to visit our Web Site, use our Service or otherwise provide information to ChargePoint, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Policy will be governed by the laws of the State of California. Any dispute arising from or relating to this Agreement shall be arbitrated in Santa Clara, California; provided that this sentence shall not apply to you if you are a citizen or resident of the European Union or Switzerland. The arbitration shall be administered by JAMS in accordance with its Comprehensive Arbitration Rules and Procedures, and judgment on any award may be entered in any court of competent jurisdiction. If the Parties agree, a mediator may be consulted prior to arbitration. All claims shall be brought in the parties’ individual capacity, and not as a plaintiff or class member in any purported class or representative proceeding. The prevailing Party in any dispute arising out of this Agreement shall be entitled to reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs; provided that this sentence shall not apply to you if you are a citizen or resident of the European Union or Switzerland. 

### 9\. EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield

ChargePoint complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. ChargePoint has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit _https://www.privacyshield.gov_.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, ChargePoint is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, ChargePoint may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, ChargePoint commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this Policy should first contact ChargePoint’s Privacy Administrator at:

Privacy Administrator 254 E. Hacienda Avenue Campbell, CA 95008

ChargePoint has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please visit <https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim> for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. Citizens and residents of the European Union or Switzerland also have the possibility, under certain conditions, to invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding Privacy Shield compliance not resolved by any of the other Privacy Shield mechanisms. For additional information go to https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction.

Finally, as a last resort and under limited circumstances, EU and Swiss individuals with residual privacy complaints may invoke a binding arbitration option before the Privacy Shield Panel.

### 10\. Contact Us

You can contact us by email at [support@chargepoint.com ](mailto:support@chargepoint.com)or write to us at: ChargePoint, Attn: Customer Service, 254 E. Hacienda Avenue, Campbell, CA 95008-6901.
